vansd.org 2018-10-13

# Web privacy statement – Vancouver Public Schools

## Vancouver Public Schools web privacy statement

Thank you for visiting Vancouver Public Schools website and reviewing our privacy policy. VPS is comprised of schools, all of which may have individual representation on the web. VPS does not collect your personally identifiable information when you visit one of our websites unless you choose to provide that information to us. This privacy policy applies only to the online activities of VPS.

### If you send us personal information

VPS websites will collect personal information, which you knowingly and voluntarily provide to us by—for example—sending emails, completing information forms, registering for accounts or responding to surveys. If you provide us with personal information, we may use it to respond to your inquiry or request.

### Information collected and stored automatically

If you visit our website, we automatically gather and store the following information about your visit so that we can track the use of our website in order to make improvements. This information includes, but is not limited to the following, and is stored and used in aggregate form only:

  * The IP address from which you access our website
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our website
  * The date and time you access our site
  * The pages, files, documents and links that you visit
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked to this website

It is not used to contact you personally.

### Cookies

We may use cookies in order to customize this site for return visitors.  These cookies are not required for site functionality.  Additionally, third-party widgets such as YouTube or Flickr may install cookies depending on their configuration.  You are not required to accept any cookies to use this site. Site visitors can turn off cookies from their browser.

**Google Analytics**

We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.

VPS may use third-party advertising and analytic companies (included, but not limited to Facebook and Twitter) to serve ads about our organization on websites across the internet. These companies may use cookies to serve you more relevant advertisements and offers across the internet based on the information about your visit to this website or other websites.

### **Linking**

Within VPS websites are widgets and other content links to non-VPS websites. These sites operate independently of VPS and have their own privacy policies. VPS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-VPS websites, and such links are not intended to be an endorsement of the non-VPS website or its content. For your protection, you should review the privacy policy of the site you linked to from our website.

### **Comments**

Questions and comments about this privacy policy may be directed to vpscommunications@vansd.org.
